# AHMET NOVALIĆ

**BACKEND DEVELOPER** 

+387 61 634 190

ahmetnovalic@gmail.com @

ahmet.com.ba



Bosnia and Herzegovina



# **ABOUT ME**

A passionate software engineer with vast experience engaging with startups and corporates in different industries, from all around the world, working on solutions from start to finish.

In many of the projects had a role of a full-stack developer, with a focus towards backend development of web applications and integrations between different systems.

Some of the technologies worked with include Python/
Flask/Django stack, with extensive experience designing and writing API integrations.

After MSc in Computer Science, gained more interest and exposure to blockchain and data science, and worked on several projects in these domains.

Working mostly remotely in recent years, with a strong work ethic and ability to work autonomously.

## **INTERESTS & HOBBIES**

Open-source, Blockchain, Al & ML, data science, cycling, running

## **LANGUAGES**

Bosnian (native)
English (IELTS and TOEFL cert.)
Basic German and Spanish

#### **WORK EXPERIENCE**

**Senior Software Developer at Reckon Digital, London, UK / 2019 - present** Working with a team of passionate Python developers on a management application that is used for the distribution of humanitarian aid by one of the world's biggest humanitarian organisations.

**Head of Engineering at DBF Connect**, Berlin, Germany / 2018 - 2019 Worked on the idea from the inception and the first drafts of the whitepaper for the new decentralised platform built on the blockchain network with the team and management from Connect Global. Later, as the team expanded, focused on building the infrastructure for the planned ICO.

**Full-stack developer at Connect Global**, Berlin, Germany / 2017 - 2018 Worked on all technical aspects of preparation for the CUBE Tech Fair 2018: creation of the website, special portal for ticket holders, mobile applications and the support tools that were used during the preparation of the events.

## Full-stack developer at Konsus, Palo Alto, USA / 2015 - 2016

The first technical team member that worked on setting the foundation and improvement of the technological stack for a YC (W16) company. Worked on integration between multiple services and on client-facing tools such a Slack bot that was featured on the Slack application store.

## Independent software and web developer / 2012 - present

Part-time work on a number of different sized projects. Got exposed to various industries and people from all around the world. A few highlights:

- created a Point-of-Sale system used via web-interface for managing the
  customers and their prepaid mobile plans in a remote USA market; more
  than 2 million USD of revenue was processed since the system was put into
  use; worked on all aspects of the project, from devops, development,
  testing, through support and maintenance
- prototyped and shipped a web app for increase of engagement on social media based on specific filters, such as keyword, location and language

## **EDUCATION**

## University of Southampton, Southampton, UK

Master of Science in Computer Science with Distinction, November 2017 Al, Web Dev., E-Business, Data Mining, Data Science, Open Data Innovation Dissertation: A novel blockchain approach for autonomous route planning Chevening Scholarship

American University in Bosnia and Herzegovina, Tuzla, BiH Bachelor of Technology in Information Technology, June 2013 GPA in major: 3.98 (A), Best in class 2013